Guide to the Cornell University calendar collection, 1902-2005.
Cornell University calendar collection,
- Series I. Chronological list of calendars
  - 2001 Cornell Calendar, 2001 (Box 5)
    The cover features "The Cornell [central campus] Skyline Viewed from West Hill" at sunset; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus (with the possibility of Weill Cornell Medical and the Shoals Marine Lab); the month of March features "The Dragon Day 2000 Parade;" the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 2001-2002, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 2001 to August 2002; features BW photographs of students or staff participating in the event listed and described at length at the photograph's side (e.g. in March, a photograph and short history of "Dragon Day" along with the dozens of events throughout the month); the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 2001 to 2002 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 2002 Cornell Calendar, 2002 (Box 5)
    The cover features "The Suspension Bridge over Fall Creek Gorge" with the leaves in autumn colors; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus (with the possibility of Weill Cornell Medical and the Shoals Marine Lab); the month of December features "The ceiling and Tiffany chandeliers of Sage Chapel" with its numerous religious symbols; the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - 2003 Calendar, 2003 (Box 5)
    The cover features the entrance to "The Biotechnology Building;" the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus (with the possibility of Weill Cornell Medical and the Shoals Marine Lab); the photograph in May shows an exterior view of "The new caf in Olin Library [Libe Caf];" the photograph in September observes a gathering of hundreds of students in memorial of 9/11 ("Twilight, Arts Quad: September 11, 2001"); the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - 2005 Calendar, 2005 (Box 5)
    The cover features the (at the time) newly constructed Duffield Hall; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus (with the possibility of Weill Cornell Medical and the Shoals Marine Lab); October's photograph is of interest, documenting "The October 2003 ceremony in Barton Hall inaugurating Jeffrey S. Lehman as Cornell's eleventh president;" the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Big Red 2005 Cornell Calendar, 2005 (Box 5)
    A calendar comprised of 15 cards (1 title, 12 months, 1 of image credits, and 1 reading the opening words of the Cornell motto), each measuring about 4 1/2" by 5 1/2", kept in a jewel case (due to the size and jewel case of the item it is kept at the top of the box); the color images range from a (very saturated) photograph of McGraw Tower at sunset (December) to scientific image illustrating an "Antibody sensor" (February) to a detail of an "Illuminated manuscript ca. 1323" from (our very own) Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections (October).
  - 2005 Calendar, 2005 (Box 5)
    The cover shows an image of Duffield Hall
  - 2006 Calendar, 2006 (Box 5)
    The cover shows an image of Sage College
  - 2008 Calendar, 2008 (Box 5)
    The cover features two students (?) standing at the Johnson Museum's Sherry and Joel Mallin Sculpture Court and observing the campus; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus (with the possibility of Weill Cornell Medical and the Shoals Marine Lab); the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - 2009 Calendar, 2009 (Box 5)
    The cover shows an image of west campus and libe slope
- Series II. Duplicates
  - 1909 Cornell Calendar, 1909 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs for each month but without titles or descriptions; the photographs are printed onto scrapbook paper and roughly trimmed, then printed in reproduction form to give the calendar a very "cosy" appearance; additionally, the calendar months are handwritten for similar effect.
  - Cornell Calendar 1909, 1909 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; cover features a color illustration of an half-naked man leaning against a stump in the green woods with a pen in his right-hand and his eyes staring thoughtfully into an easel we cannot see, giving the illustration a very sylvan, "dales of Arcady" atmosphere--a vision of the Arts Quad appears in a silver frame in the center; features BW photographs of the campus for each month with titles underneath.
  - Cornell 1911, 1911 (Box 6)
    Three duplicates; one duplicate lacks front and back covers and the loose leaves are busheled together with another duplicate; features BW photographs for each month with descriptions on back of calendar.
  - Cornell 1912, 1912 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; the duplicate lacks a binding; the cover depicts a color reproduction of "Senior Singing," an oil painting designed and painted by Christian Midjo; features BW photographs of the campus for each month with descriptions on back of calendar.
  - Cornell University, 1914 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; the duplicate lacks a binding; both calendars are missing a bottom flap which unfolds to reveal the days of the months i.e. the actual calendar; includes 15 leaves of really stunning BW photography depicting the winter weather of Ithaca, Cornell's campus, students between class or out sporting and (presumably in June) graduating, etc.; descriptions of the photographs on back of calendar.
  - Cornell 1914, 1914 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; leather cover with Cornell University shield imprinted; features BW photographs of the capmus throughout with titles underneath.
  - 1915 Cornell University, 1915 (Box 6)
    Three duplicates; the duplicate calendars have no binding; the duplicates lack the bottom flap which unfolds to reveal the days of the months i.e. the actual calendar; the cover was designed by Christian Midjo; includes 15 leaves of really stunning BW photography depicting the winter weather of Ithaca, Cornell's campus, students between class or out sporting and (presumably in June) graduating, etc.
  - Cornell University 1916, 1916 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs for each month with descriptions on back of calendar; the month of October features "First touchdown by Captain Barrett, in First Game of Football played on Schoellkopf Field, Gettysburg-Cornell, September 28, 1915" in addition to a full page of three photographs documenting the "Harvard-Cornell [football game] at Cambridge, Oct. 23, 1915," the score ending "Harvard, 0: Cornell, 10."
  - 1917 Cornell University, 1917 (Box 6)
    Three duplicates; two duplicates are missing the cover image whereas the cover image on the other duplicate is torn and loose; however, both duplicates have the months of January and December which are missing from the "original;" the cover depicts a color reproduction of an oil painting of Goldwin Smith Hall and the A.D. White statue--the faint signature of "C.M.S. Midjo" (Christian Midjo[?]) is in the lower right corner; a card on the back of the cover quotes the poem, "Andrew Dickson White," by Albert W. Smith, reading: "Here 'mid the fair fulfillment of his dream / His statue broods above the busy ways;" features BW photographs for each month with descriptions beneath each photograph; a photograph of "Ex-President Taft" and "President Schurman" is featured for April.
  - Cornell University 1918 Calendar, 1918 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; the top right corner of the duplicate exhibits nibbling by some animal; cover features a colored-in photograph of the Cornell campus and Cayuga Lake faintly in the background; features many exceptional colored-in photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; the bottom flap folds down to reveal the days of the month i.e. the actual calendar.
  - 1919 Cornell University, 1919 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; the duplicate has a (mendable) tear across the back; the cover features a BW photograph of the Ezra Cornell statue in the Cornell Arts Quad; a bottom flap unfolds to to reveal the days of the months i.e. the actual calendar; there are many BW photographs (with titles underneath) depicting the Cornell R.O.T.C. training about campus.
  - Cornell 1921, 1921 (Box 6)
    Two duplicates; a colored-in photograph of McGraw Tower is center on the cover; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the campus and student life and sports.
  - Cornell 1921, 1921 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; the duplicate has no binding; black leather cover with the Cornell shield imprinted bottom-center; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of various Cornell campus buildings; curiously, the calendar lists the dates of the moon cycles (i.e. "First Quarter," "Full Moon," "Last Quarter," and "New Moon") above or below each month.
  - 1922 Cornell, 1922 (Box 6)
    One duplicate; duplicate is missing the BW photograph of McGraw Tower on the front cover (also, it has "Duplicate" handwritten in pencil on the top right corner); the cover includes a quote by Albert W. Smith, reading, "Hail Thou in Majesty, Cornell, on Guard Forever on the Height;" features BW photographs (with titles underneath) depicting the campus and student life and sports; two photographs of interest (in October) are: 1) "Mr. George F. Baker Laying the Corner-stone of the New Chemistry Building--His Gift to Cornell University;" and, 2) "The Inauguration. The New President Livingston Farrand and Acting President A.W. Smith."
  - 1923 Cornell University, 1923 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; the cover photograph is missing on the duplicate and the condition is worn-out; the leaves for the months of January and March are folded over; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the campus and student life and sports, including a (small) photograph (in July) of what appears to be mostly if not all men swimming in the Fall Creek Gorge and another (small) photograph (in September) of "maidens" retrieving arrows from a target during an archery class (with a clever quote below, reading, "More merciful than Cupid, who ne'er / withdraws a dart once sped," written by Albert W. Smith).
  - 1923 Cornell Calendar of Winter and Spring Events and the Reunions, 1923 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; a small calendar published to advertise the 21 different Cornell class reunions (ranging from the years 1873 to 1921) all to be held on June 15th through the 17th; the drawing (of the Arts Quad at the calendar's top) is by "J. Andr Smith '02" and the lettering is by "John T. Parson '99;" the calendar features individual leaves for the months of January through June with a reminder-note to sign up for the class reunion; the following months of July through December are all on the back of the calendar.
  - Cornell 1924, 1924 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; duplicate is incomplete and is missing the binding, the cover, and the back (it is being kept in a manila folder); features sepia-colored photographs (with titles underneath) depicting the campus and student life, including two photographs of the moonlight on the campus in April and two photographs of "The Mud Rush" in May; exceptional photographs in this calendar.
  - Cornell 1924, 1924 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; the duplicate is in extremely poor condition, with the back and front covers deteriorating; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the campus and student life; one photograph (in March) depicts three "Bronze Statues [The Boy with a Thorn; Discus Thrower; and, Praying Boy] from the large collection in the Museum of Archeology representing the best of Greek sculpture."
  - Cornell 1925, 1925 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; the cover photo of the duplicate is missing; includes sepia-toned photographs of the campus, the student life and sports, and several of the Cornell R.O.T.C. training; two (albeit small) photographs of the "The Mud Battle" are in May.
  - 1925 Cornell, 1925 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; duplicate is incomplete and is missing the cover and the months of January and February; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) mostly of the academic buildings on campus in addition to several photographs of student life and sports; includes (in August) an illustration of Willard Straight Hall "by the Architects, Messrs. Delano and Aldritch."
  - (Loose Leaves of) 1925 Cornell, 1925 (Box 7)
    The leaves for the months of October and December for the "1925 Cornell" calendar; loose leaves are packed at the top of the box.
  - 1926 Cornell Calendar of Winter and Spring Events and the Reunions, 1926 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; a small calendar published to advertise the 19 different Cornell class reunions (ranging from the years 1871 to 1924) all to be held on June 11th through the 13th; the drawing (of the Arts Quad at the calendar's top) is by "J. Andr Smith '02" and the lettering is by "John T. Parson '99;" the calendar features individual leaves for the months of January through June with a reminder-note to sign up for the class reunion and the promise that "June 1926 should surpass all previous celebrations;" the following months of July through December are all on the back of the calendar.
  - (Loose Leaf of) Cornell 1926, 1926 (Box 7)
    The leaf for the month of January for the "Cornell 1926" calendar; loose leaves are packed at the top of the box.
  - Cornell 1926, 1926 (Box 7)
    One duplicate; a colored-in photograph of the Arts Quad is on the center of the cover; sepia-toned photographs (with titles underneath) for each month depict campus, student life and sports; two photographs for the month of January document astronomical phenomena: 1) "Total Eclipse of the Sun from Cornell, January 24, 1925;" and, 2) "The Corona of the Eclipse;" the faces and bodies of people in several of the photos appear to have been "touched-up" with pencil in the pre-publishing process.
  - 1926 Cornell, 1926 (Box 7)
    Four duplicates; one duplicate is out of order, going from June to October (with the second October leaf preceding the first leaf), and then going September, August, July, and then November; the cover of another duplicate is badly worn and the cover photograph is torn and loose; a BW photograph of the Arts Quad is center on the cover; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the campus and student goings-on; one photograph of note is "President Farrand's Commencement Address, June 15, 1925" (in June); additionally, one photograph (in December) features "Professor Kinkeldey, Professor Harold Smith, and the Advanced Choir of Sage Chapel."
  - Cornell 1927, 1927 (Box 7)
    Four duplicates; A colored-in photograph of McGraw Tower is on the center of the cover; BW photographs (with titles underneath) for each month depict campus, student life and sports, including one photograph wherein "President Farrand decorates the prize-winning cadets of the R.O.T.C." (for the month of April).
  - 1928 Cornell, 1928 (Box 7)
    Four duplicates; the two duplicates are both in bad condition; one lacks the title photograph (a colored-in photograph of Willard Straight Hall and Lake Cayuga in the background) whereas the other lacks a cover outright; another duplicate has the months of November and December in reverse; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the campus and student goings-on; "J.F. Anderson" and "N.G. Wright" are featured in May for track and field events; in the photograph for June, "Dexter Kimball" is seen leading the "Senior Singing on the Steps of Goldwin Smith Hall;" in the photograph for December, "Commander Byrd pays tribute to the memory of Ross Gilmore Marvin, Cornell, 1905, at Sage Chapel."
  - (Loose Leaves of) Cornell 1929, 1929 (Box 8)
    The cover and the leaf for the month of August for the "Cornell 1929" calendar; loose leaves are packed at the top of the box.
  - Cornell MCMXXIX, 1929 (Box 8)
    Two duplicates; the cover features a colored-in photograph of the A.D. White statue and the Arts Quad with McGraw Tower in the background; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and major events (e.g. sports and commencement).
  - Cornell 1930, 1930 (Box 8)
    Four duplicates; cover features a color photograph of the Ezra Cornell statue; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); the photograph "Beacham's Band Makes Its Debut at the Niagra Game" in November is of interest.
  - Cornell 1930, 1930 (Box 8)
    Two duplicates; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement).
  - Cornell 1931, 1931 (Box 8)
    Three duplicates; cover features a colored-in photograph of the Cornell War Memorial; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); there is a small "Architects Sketch of Myron Taylor Hall" for the month of August.
  - Cornell 1931, 1931 (Box 8)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes three aerial-view photographs of the campus (with one of "Schoellkopf Field during Princeton Game" in November).
  - Cornell 1932, 1932 (Box 8)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); the photograph of "The Library from the War Memorial Archway" in October is particularly pleasant; also includes two aerial-view photographs of the campus.
  - Cornell 1933, 1933 (Box 8)
    Two duplicates; one duplicate has pencil shadings on the "1933" of the title, drawings of arrows about the title photograph, and a handwritten note in the top left corner, reading: "S[5?]O 2-7223 / oil B[illegible];" features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes two aerial-view photographs of the campus.
  - Cornell 1934, 1934 (Box 8)
    Three duplicates; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement), with one photograph of "The Junior Prom" (in February) and one of "President Farrand addressing the Class of 1933" (in June); also includes two aerial-view photographs of the campus (in April).
  - Cornell 1935, 1935 (Box 9)
    Three duplicates; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes one aerial-view photograph of the "College of Agriculture."
  - Cornell 1936, 1936 (Box 9)
    One duplicate; the duplicate has "#2070-" handwritten in pencil in top left corner of cover; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); "Jack Batten" and "Jeff Stofer" are featured in football photographs in November; also includes one aerial-view photograph of the campus.
  - (Loose Leaf of) Cornell 1937, 1937 (Box 9)
    The leaf for the month of July for the "Cornell 1937" calendar; loose leaves are packed at the top of the box.
  - Cornell 1937, 1937 (Box 9)
    Five duplicates; one duplicate has "#2070-" handwritten in pencil in top left corner of cover; the binding of another duplicate is undone; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes two aerial-view photographs of the campus.
  - Cornell 1938, 1938 (Box 9)
    Three duplicates; one duplicate includes the days of the month on tissue paper which was glued onto the calendar leaf (as opposed to the days of the month being printed on); features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes three aerial-view photographs of the campus.
  - Cornell 1939, 1939 (Box 10)
    One duplicate; the cover features the Cornell shield; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; most of the photographs for both the "original" and the duplicate are loose (though all are present); the photograph of the "Interior View of Willard Straight Hall" for the month of March is unique.
  - Cornell 1941, 1941 (Box 10)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; duplicate cover is slightly water-damaged (?) and wavy; a scenic photograph of the "Willard Straight Rock Garden" is featured for June.
  - Cornell 1942, 1942 (Box 10)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; the month of May features an uncommon (and somewhat perspectiveless) photograph of "Cayuga Lake from Stewart Avenue Bridge;" a BW illustration of the "Entrance to Balch Hall at Night" is depicted for December.
  - Cornell 1946, 1946 (Box 10)
    One duplicate; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; the picture for June offers "A Glimpse of 'Collegetown'" (at approximately the intersection of Williams St., Eddy St., and Dryden Rd. ) in 1946.
  - 1993 Cornell Calendar, 1993 (Box 10)
    One duplicate; the cover features McGraw Tower at night, the moon in its third-quarter ghostly in the violet sky; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the photograph for July shows "Dedication ceremonies for Akwe:kon, the Native American residential program house;" the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1994-1995, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
    One duplicate; an academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1994 to August 1995; the month of March features a BW photograph of the Dragon Day Parade (the year of the parade, however, is uncredited) with a short history included; the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1994 to 1995 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1995 Cornell Calendar, 1995 (Box 10)